Register of the Albert C. Wedemeyer papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- PHOTOGRAPHS, circa 1897-1987 (Boxes 153-163)
  - 14 prints of Franklin Roosevelt in French Morocco, Liberia, Brazil, and in transit during his trip to the Casablanca Conference, undated (Box 158, Envelope EE)
    Includes photographs of Edwin Barclay, Mark Clark, Louis graphs of Edwin Barclay, Mark Clark, Louis Mountbatten, George Patton, Getulio Vargas and others.
  - 18 prints relating to the Quebec conference, including photographs of Henry H. Arnold, Alexander Cadogan, Winston Churchill, Anthony Eden, Thomas T. Handy, Ernest King, William Leahy, George Marshall, Louis Mountbatten, Franklin Roosevelt and others, 1943 August (Box 158, Envelope FF)
  - 1 print of participants at the Teheran Conference including Winston Churchill, Anthony Eden, Viacheslav Molotov, Franklin D. Roosevelt, Joseph Stalin and others, 1943 November (Box 158, Envelope GG)
  - 5 prints of participants at the Cairo Conference, including Chiang Kai-shek, Mei-ling Soong Chiang, Winston Churchill, Franklin Roosevelt and others, 1943 December (Box 158, Envelope HH)
  - 42 prints (2 duplicates) of Albert Wedemeyer and colleagues, including Patrick Hurley, Chiang Kai-shek, Louis Mountbatten, George Stratemeyer and others, during assignment with the Southeast Asia Command, 1943-1944 (Box 158, Envelope II)
  - 74 prints (4 duplicates) of interior and exterior building scenes, probably Albert Wedemeyer's offices and quarters during assignment with the Southeast Asia Command, 1943-1944 (Box 159, Envelope JJ)
  - 3 prints related to the rescue of pilots from the Doolittle raid on Japan, 1942-1946; 2 prints of headquarters facilities in China; 1 print of Chiang Kai-shek with a group of Chinese officers; 24 prints of American and Chinese military and civilian officials, including Chen Cheng, Chiang Kai-shek, Chou En-lai, Claire Chennault, Ho Ying-chin, Robert McClure, Walter Robertson, Jonathan Wainwright and others, 1943-1945 (Box 159, Envelope KK)
  - 12 prints (4 duplicates) of Albert Wedemeyer and military colleagues in China, including Adrian Carton De Wiart, Chester Nimitz and others; 10 prints (3 duplicates) of Albert Wedemeyer, circa 1945-1946 (Box 159, Envelope LL)
  - 2 prints of Albert Wedemeyer and Claire Chennault, circa 1944; 113 prints (16 duplicates) of Albert Wedemeyer on inspection tours in China and Burma, 1944-1946 (Box 159, Envelope MM-OO)
    Includes photographs of Claire Chennault, William Donovan, Patrick Hurley, Louis Mountbatten, Daniel Sultan and others.
  - 5 prints of General Wedemeyer's airplane; 3 prints of scenes of Chinese cities, circa 1944-1946; 2 prints of the victory parade in Chungking, 1945; 25 prints (1 duplicate) of General Wedemeyer's staff and quarters in Shanghai, Nanking and Chungking, circa 1944-1946 (Box 159, Envelope PP)
  - 12 prints of a parade in Tokyo, Japan, circa 1945; 8 prints of George Marshall in China, and 13 prints of Albert Wedemeyer and others at a banquet (in honor of General Marshall?), circa 1945-1946; 2 prints (1 duplicate) of Albert Wedemeyer receiving a medal from Dwight Eisenhower, circa 1946 (Box 159, Envelope QQ)
  - 86 prints (14 duplicates) of Albert Wedemeyer in China with various military colleagues and other individuals, including Chen Cheng, Claire Chennault, Chiang Kai-shek, Charles M. Cooke, Patrick Hurley, Charles Turner Joy, Robert B. McClure, Robert Patterson, Prince Peter of Greece, T.V. Soong, Jonathan Wainwright and others, 1944-1946 (Box 159, Envelope RR)
  - 86 prints (14 duplicates) of Albert Wedemeyer in China with various military colleagues and other individuals, including Chen Cheng, Claire Chennault, Chiang Kai-shek, Charles M. Cooke, Patrick Hurley, Charles Turner Joy, Robert B. McClure, Robert Patterson, Prince Peter of Greece, T.V. Soong, Jonathan Wainwright and others (cont'd.), 1944-1946 (Box 160, Envelope SS-TT)
  - 25 prints of Chiang Kai-shek and Mei-ling Soong Chiang, and 1 drawing (plus 3 duplicates) of Chiang Kai-shek, circa 1944-1950 (Box 160, Envelope UU)
    Includes photographs with Clare Boothe Luce, George Marshall and others.
  - 12 prints of Chinese Communist leaders: Chen Yi, Chou En-lai, Chu Hsi, Chu Teh, Ho Lung, Lin Biu, Liu Pai Cheng, Mao Tse-tung, Nieh Jung Chien, Peng Te Huai, Tung Pi Wu, and Yeh Chien Ying, 1946 (Box 160, Envelope VV)
  - 56 prints (4 duplicates) of the Wedemeyer Mission in China or in transit, 1947 (Box 160, Envelope WW)
  - 42 prints (2 duplicates) of Albert Wedemeyer at social and military functions while assigned to the Second Army, circa 1946-1947; 3 prints of the Wedemeyer home at Ft. Meade, Maryland (Box 160, Envelope XX-YY)
  - 17 prints (2 duplicates) of Albert Wedemeyer during his assignment as Director of the Plans and Operations Division of the General Staff, with various civilian and military personnel, including Omar Bradley, Pyung-Ok Chough, James Forrestal, Ho Ying-chin, Alan Ladd, Lauris Norstad, Arthur Radford and others, circa 1947-1948 (Box 160, Envelope ZZ)
  - 13 prints (2 duplicates) relating to a trip by General and Mrs. Wedemeyer to England and Europe, 1947; 25 prints relating to a trip to Europe by William H. Draper, circa 1947-1948 [See also: Box 155] (Box 160, Envelope AAA)
  - 4 prints of Albert Wedemeyer and others during his assignment as Deputy Chief of Staff for Plans and Combat Operations, circa 1948-1949 (Box 160, Envelope BBB)
  - 66 prints relating to Kenneth Royall's trip to Japan, undated (Box 161, Envelope CCC)
    Includes photographs of Douglas MacArthur and others.
  - 26 prints (4 duplicates) of Albert Wedemeyer with others, including, Frank Pace, Lowell Thomas and others, attending military and civic functions during his assignment with the Sixth Army, 1949-1951; 2 prints of Albert Wedemeyer, 1949-1950 (Box 161, Envelope DDD)
  - 57 prints (1 duplicate) of Albert Wedemeyer during his assignment with the Sixth Army, reviewing military installations and with military colleagues including Mark Clark, J. Lawton Collins, Frank Pace, Matthew Ridgway, Kenneth Royall, Walter Bedell Smith and others, 1949-1951 (Box 161, Envelope EEE-FFF)
  - 5 prints of Albert Wedemeyer, Douglas MacArthur, Earl Warren and others during a welcoming ceremony for MacArthur in San Francisco, 1951; 16 prints relating to Wedemeyer's retirement, 1951; 6 prints of San Francisco and the Wedemeyer home at the Presidio, circa 1949-1951 (Box 161, Envelope GGG)
  - 21 prints of maps relating to World War II, primarily in the Philippines; 2 prints of maps of World War II European invasion routes, 1944-1945; 1 print of Cherbourg, France; 5 prints of scenes and military personnel in the Pacific during the war (Box 161, Envelope HHH)
  - 12 prints of scenes in Japan, 1947-1948; 2 postcards relating to Japanese ships, undated; 8 prints of Japanese military personnel and others at a reception for Albery Wedemeyer, 1968 (Box 162, Envelope III)
  - 25 prints of Albert Wedemeyer with military groups and individuals, including Mark Clark, Dwight Eisenhower, Curtis LeMay, Louis Mountbatten and others, undated and post-retirement, circa 1952-1965 (Box 162, Envelope JJJ)
    Includes 3 photographs relating to trip by Albert Wedemeyer to Berlin, 1957.
  - 22 prints of military groups and individuals, including Omar Bradley, Dwight Eisenhower, Charles Turner Joy, Douglas MacArthur, George Marshall, Chester Nimitz, John Pershing and others, circa 1918-1975; 1 photograph of an airplane (Box 162, Envelope KKK)
  - 43 portraits prints (some inscribed) and 2 negatives of military colleagues of Albert Wedemeyer, including Paul Caraway, Claire Chennault, Mark Clark, James H. Doolittle, Dwight Eisenhower, Thomas Handy, Hastings Ismay, Ernest J. King, Charles Turner Joy, Louis Mountbatten, Henry R Pownall, Arthur Radford, Alden Sibley, George Stratemeyer, Jonathan M. Wainwright, Ivan Yeaton and others, circa 1943-1971 (Box 162, Envelope LLL-MMM)
  - 16 prints (2 duplicates) (some inscribed) of Albert Wedemeyer and political figures, including Spiro Agnew, Jesse Helms, Herbert Hoover, Richard Nixon, Ronald Reagan, Robert H. Taft, and George Wallace, circa 1952-1980s (Box 162, Envelope NNN)
  - 43 prints( 1 duplicate) some inscribed) of friends and colleagues of Albert Wedemeyer, including Constantine Brown, Huntington Cairns, Chiang Kai-shek, Manton Eddy, Bernard R. Hubbard, John E. Hull, Patrick Hurley, Charles A. Lindbergh, Douglas MacArthur, Kenneth Royall, J. Leighton Stuart, Hollington Tong, Harry S. Truman and others, 1947-1971 (Box 162, Envelope OOO)
  - 43 prints( 1 duplicate) some inscribed) of friends and colleagues of Albert Wedemeyer, including Constantine Brown, Huntington Cairns, Chiang Kai-shek, Manton Eddy, Bernard R. Hubbard, John E. Hull, Patrick Hurley, Charles A. Lindbergh, Douglas MacArthur, Kenneth Royall, J. Leighton Stuart, Hollington Tong, Harry S. Truman and others (cont'd.), 1947-1971 (Box 163, Envelope mRRR)
  - 8 prints (1 duplicate of RR) of friends and colleagues of Albert Wedemeyer in China and Taiwan, including Chen Cheng, Claire Chennault, Chiang Kai-shek, Wei-kuo (Wego) Chiang, Patrick Hurley, and Peter Pee, 1944-1969; 2 prints of General Wedemeyer's airplane in China, 1945 (Box 163, Envelope mSSS)
  - 11 portrait prints (6 duplicates) and 1 drawing of Albert Wedemeyer's cousin, Thomas O'Hara; 5 prints of a resolution honoring O'Hara, 1959 (Box 163, Envelope mTTT)
  - 1 print of participants at the Quebec Conference, August 1943 (duplicate of print in Envelope FF); 1 print relating to the welcoming ceremony for Douglas MacArthur in San Francisco (duplicate of print in Envelope GGG); 1 print of Albert Wedemeyer and friends at the Bohemian Grove, 1972; 1 drawing and 1 photograph of Albert Wedemeyer, 1959-1962; 1 U.S. Military Academy graduation photograph (incomplete), 1919 (Box 163, Envelope mUUU)
  - 2 portraits of Albert Wedemeyer; 4 portraits of Omar Bradley, Mark Clark, J. Lawton Collins and another, circa 1950-1951 (Box 163, Envelope mVVV)
- MOTION PICTURE FILMS (Film shelf)
  - "Barry Goldwater Campaign Film," 16mm film, 1964
  - "Goldwater Brunch Film," 16mm film
- SOUND RECORDINGS, 1952-1970 (Record cabinet, Cassette cabinet)
  - Sound discs (audiographs) (Record cabinet)
    19 recordings of speeches by Wedemeyer and others.
    - Albert C. Wedemeyer speech, "The Truth About Korea,", 1952 November 2
      Access
      Use copy reference number: 83007_a_0001496
      Introduction by John Wayne. WOR-TV telecast.
    - Dwight D. Eisenhower speech concerning the domestic economy and the prosperity of the nation, 1953 January 4
      Use copy reference number: 83007_a_0001497
    - Dwight D. Eisenhower speech concerning the Russian situation and U.S-Soviet relations, 1953 April 16
      Use copy reference number: 83007_a_0001498
    - Double Ten anniversary celebration, 1953 October 9
      Use copy reference number: 83007_a_0001499
      This is the 42nd "Double Ten" anniversary and "China Day" dinner in the Grand Ballroom of the Waldorf Astoria Hotel. Includes speeches by Chih Meng, Shing Tai Liang, P. H. Chang, Charles Edison, J. L. McNulty, Walter E. Ditmars, J. A. Van Fleet, and K. C. Wu.
    - Herbert Brownell and J. Edgar Hoover speech, 1953 November
      Use copy reference number: 83007_a_0001500
      Relates to Harry Dexter White.
    - Harry S. Truman radio broadcast, 1953 November 16
      Use copy reference number: 83007_a_0001501
      Harry Truman sounds off in regard to the Harry Dexter White situation and particularly criticizing Herbert Brownell and the Republican Party. Recorded from radio station WTHT, Hartford, Connecticut.
    - Joseph R. McCarthy speech, 1953 November 24
      Use copy reference number: 83007_a_0001502
    - Dwight D. Eisenhower address, 1953 December 8
      Use copy reference number: 83007_a_0001503
      Speech to the United Nations on atomic weapons.
    - Richard M. Nixon address, 1953 December 23
      Use copy reference number: 83007_a_0001504
      Report on his trip as vice president to the Far East.
    - Dwight D. Eisenhower address, 1954 January 7
      Use copy reference number: 83007_a_0001505
      State of the Union message.
    - Clarence Manion, "The Constitution is Your Business,", 1954 January 25
      Use copy reference number: 83007_a_0001506
      Relates to the Bricker Amendment to the U.S. Constitution.
    - A. Tyler Port audiogram, description of Korean front and liberation of P.W.'s, reported from Manila, Philippines, 1954 February 9
      Use copy reference number: 83007_a_0001507 (part)
    - William Heimlich, 1954 February 9
      Report by assistant to W. E. Ditamrs on trip to Formosa (Taiwan) and Hong Kong, including a dinner with Chiang Kai-shek.
    - Joseph R. McCarthy interview on the Fulton Lewis Jr. Program, 1954 March 11
      Use copy reference number: 83007_a_0001508
    - Richard M. Nixon, 1954 March 13
      Use copy reference number: 83007_a_0001509
      Reply to Adlai Stevenson.
    - Dwight D. Eisenhower, 1954 March 15
      Use copy reference number: 83007_a_0001510
      Relates to taxes.
    - Dwight D. Eisenhower, 1956 February 29
      Use copy reference number: 83007_a_0001511
      Press conference, 10:30 a.m., and speech, 10 p.m.
  - One sound cassette of two speeches by Albert Wedemeyer: Washington, D.C., August 12; and United States Military Academy, September 12, 1970 (Cassette cabinet)
- INCREMENTAL MATERIALS (Box 152)
  Not yet described.